不知道你有没有这种感觉，巴黎 2024 年奥运会感觉好像就是昨天的事，
I don't know about you, but the Paris 2024 Olympics seems like only yesterday,
但现在已经是 2026 年了，这意味着我们距离下一届奥运会已经过了一半，
but it's now 2026, which means we're already halfway towards the next games,
而这届奥运会可是设定了相当雄心勃勃的目标。
and this one has set some pretty ambitious targets.
零新建场馆，并且定位为一场"无车出行"的盛会。
There will be zero new venues, and it's being positioned as a nocar event.
那么，这届奥运会到底在哪里举办来着？
So, remind me where's this being held again?
>> 没错，就是洛杉矶。
>> That's right, Los Angeles.
尽管洛杉矶有着辉煌的奥运历史，但这座城市的公共交通可不是出了名的好，
Despite having a strong Olympic past, LA isn't exactly known for its public transit
在 2028 年夏季奥运会之前，还有许多挑战等待克服。
and has numerous other challenges to overcome before the summer of 2028.
那么，这些挑战具体是什么？
So, what are those challenges?
这座城市能及时做好准备吗？
And can this city be ready in time?
举办奥运会在财务、社会和环境方面的负担正变得越来越沉重。
It's becoming enormously burdensome financially, socially, environmentally to host the Olympic Games.
如果洛杉矶无法胜任，
If Los Angeles can't pull it off,
我认为这对未来有意申办的城市将是更大的打击。
then I think it's going to be even more discouraging to potential future cities.
>> 把年份从 2024 换到 2028，
>> Moving the hashtag from 2024 to 2028, Los Angeles has decided
洛杉矶决定再多等四年。
it can wait it out an extra four years.
2017 年，当洛杉矶获得 2028 年奥运会主办权时，
When LA was awarded the 2028 Olympics back in 2017,
情况实属反常。
the situation was far from normal.
就在同一场会议上，巴黎拿下了 2024 年的主办权。
Paris was given the 2024 games at the very same event.
两届奥运会主办城市同时公布，这在历史上从未有过。
Two host cities had never before been announced together.
但这背后是有充分理由的。
But there were good reasons for this.
>> 当时已经非常清楚，国际奥委会（IOC）在寻找愿意举办奥运会的城市方面遭遇了巨大困难。
>> It became very clear that the IOC was having enormous difficulties
finding cities that wanted to host the games.
实际上，在 2024 年奥运会的申办过程中，整整有四座城市——
And indeed, the potential hosting for the 2024 games had four cities,
四座城市——先后退出了竞争。
four cities that had been bidding to host the games drop out.
2017 年做出最终决定时，剩下的申办者只有两个，
When they made their decision in 2017, there were only two biders left
一个是巴黎，一个是洛杉矶。
and one was Paris and one was Los Angeles.
两者都是稳健的选择。
They were both good bets.
尽管巴黎拿到了 2024 年，洛杉矶仍然实力雄厚，
Although Paris got 2024, LA was still a strong contender
同意再等四年——以换取额外资金支持，
and agreed to wait another four years in return for extra funding,
这笔钱正好派上用场，毕竟下一届赛事预计花费约 70 亿美元。
which was helpful because the next tournament is expected to cost around $7 billion.
让美国第二大城市在 2028 年成为优选的原因，不仅仅是
What made America's Second City a good bet for 2028 wasn't just
避免了又一轮申办者寥寥的尴尬局面。
that it would avoid another awkward round of bids
from a dwindling number of candidates later on.
不，更重要的是，洛杉矶已经有两次成功举办的经验。
No, it's the fact that it's already been there and done it twice.
第一次可以追溯到 1932 年，正值大萧条期间。
The first occasion was way back in 1932, taking place during the Great Depression.
与四年前阿姆斯特丹奥运会相比，那届参赛运动员的人数缩水了一半。
There were half as many athletes competing compared to Amsterdam 4 years earlier.
但这并没有阻止当时创纪录的 10 万名观众涌入开幕式现场。
But that didn't stop a then record-breaking 100,000 people turning up for the opening ceremony.
时间快进半个世纪，1984 年洛杉矶奥运会再度遭遇参赛国减少的困境，
Fast forward half a century, and LA 1984 once again saw fewer countries competing,
这次是因为苏联阵营的抵制。
this time due to a boycott from the Soviet block.
然而，卡尔·刘易斯摘得四枚金牌，
And yet you had Carl Lewis winning four gold medals,
迈克尔·乔丹率队称霸篮球赛场，
Michael Jordan top scoring in the basketball,
更令人惊叹的是，那届奥运会竟然实现了超过 2.5 亿美元的实际盈利。
and incredibly, the games finished with an actual profit of over $250 million.
2028 年，洛杉矶将成为历史上首座三度举办奥运会的城市，
2028 will see Los Angeles become the first city to hold the Olympics
延续前两届东道主开创的先例。
three times, and it'll continue a trend set by the two previous hosts.
巴黎和东京都将重心放在了场馆复用上，而非大兴土木。
Both Paris and Tokyo focused on reusing venues rather than building lots of new ones.
这样做不仅降低了成本，
Not only did that reduce cost,
也避免了斥巨资兴建大型场馆后，它们沦为白象工程（耗资巨大却难以持续利用的设施）的命运，
it also avoided them spending huge amounts of money on giant arenas
这种情况我们在过去已经屡见不鲜。
that could go on to become white elephants like we've seen in the past.
巴黎树立了标杆——95% 的场馆已提前建成。
Paris set the bar with 95% of its stadiums already existing.
而洛杉矶的目标更为激进：完全不新建任何场馆。
But LA plans to raise it even further, going ahead without any new construction whatsoever.
这也不难理解。
And you can kind of understand why.
洛杉矶现有的大多数场馆状况良好，
Most of his stadiums are in very good shape
几乎不需要什么额外改造，或者本身就是近年新建的。
and hardly need anything doing to them or have been recently constructed anyway.
比如全新的 Intuit Dome，现在是 NBA 快船队的主场。
Take the brand new into it dome now home to the Clippers of the NBA.
不用猜也知道——
No prizes for guessing.
篮球比赛就在这里打。
That's where you're going to find the basketball.
道奇体育场将用于棒球比赛。
Dodger Stadium is going to be for yeah baseball.
至于惠蒂尔纳罗斯射击中心嘛，它当然是办射击比赛的。
And the wittier narrows Clay Shooting Center isn't going to be hosting the dress arch.
虽然部分场馆的用途显而易见，
While some of the venue choices are obvious,
但并非所有场馆都会以你想象的方式来使用，
not all of them are being used in the way you might think,
还有一些场馆在 2028 年赛事开始前需要相当大规模的升级改造。
and others need a fair bit of upgrading
before they're ready for the 2028 games.
以全新的 SoFi 体育场为例，它主要为 NFL 而建，
Take the new SoFi Stadium, primarily built for NFL
目前已安排在 2026 年举办国际足联世界杯赛事，
and now set to host FIFA World Cup matches in 2026
2027 年承接超级碗。
along with the Super Bowl in 2027.
但到了 2028 年，SoFi 体育场不会举办足球或美式橄榄球赛事——
But in 2028, SoFi won't be hosting the footy or American football,
后者甚至根本不是奥运项目。
which isn't even in the Olympics.
届时，观众来到这里观看的，猜猜是什么——游泳！
Instead, fans are going to come here to watch, wait for it, swimming.
这座有史以来造价最高的体育场，将被改造成
The most expensive stadium ever built is going to be converted
奥运史上规模最大的水上运动专用场馆，设有 4 万个席位。
into the largest dedicated aquatics venue in Olympics history with 40,000 seats.
至于具体如何实现，目前方案尚未对外公布，
Now, the exact details of how they plan to do that aren't known yet,
但显然需要在球场中央建造一座大型游泳池，
but obviously it's going to involve constructing a large pool
而这座泳池在同年晚些时候 NFL 赛季开始前，
in the middle of the stadium, one that will have to be removed again
还必须重新拆除。
before the NFL season starts later that year.
这将是一项浩大的工程，但巴黎已经证明这类事情是可以做到的。
It'll be a massive undertaking, but Paris proved this sort of thing can be done.
那座为 2024 年奥运会临时建造的游泳池，仅用了一个多月就竣工了。
This temporary pool built for the 2024 games was constructed in just over a month.
在 SoFi 体育场复制类似的方案，
Doing something similar at Sofi is going to put swimming
将让游泳这项运动获得远比洛杉矶上届奥运会时更大的舞台。
on a much bigger platform than when LA last hosted the Olympics.
我很喜欢他们 1984 年在南加州大学使用的那个场馆，
I like the the venue that they had at USC
但他们认为那里无法提供理想的比赛环境。
at University of Southern California, uh, which they used in 1984,
but they felt like it it didn't provide the environment that was ideal.
从向全球电视观众展示奥运会、
It probably makes some sense from the standpoint of showing the Olympics
展示洛杉矶最佳面貌的角度来看，这个决定确实有一定道理。
and showing Los Angeles in its best light on international television.
原本的方案是由 SoFi 体育场主办闭幕式，
The original idea was for SoFi to hold the closing ceremony as well
洛杉矶纪念体育场负责开幕式，但计划已有所调整。
with the LA Memorial Coliseum handling the opener, but plans have changed slightly.
开幕式现在将由两座体育场联合举办。
The opening ceremony is now going to be co-hosted by both stadiums.
事实上，洛杉矶纪念体育场也是一座标志性场馆，
In fact, the Colosseum is another iconic venue
即将迎来一番改造——就像大多数奥运体育场一样，
that's set to undergo a bit of a transformation
它也将承接田径比赛。
because like most Olympic stadiums, it's also going to be used for athletics.
但这里存在一个问题。
Except there's a problem.
1990 年翻修时，场馆下层看台周围增加了大量座位，
When it was upgraded in 1990, a lot of extra seating was added
容量虽然提升了，
in around the lower tiers, which meant more capacity,
但却几乎没有留下任何空间给田径场馆最不可缺少的东西——跑道。
but little room for something that every track and field venue needs, a track.
他们打算在场地地板上建造一个临时平台，
What they intend to do is build a temporary deck
由支撑结构撑起。
on the floor of the bowl, propped up on supports.
这样就能在上层辟出跑道和田赛区域，
This will create the track and field as well as space underneath
下方空间则供运动员热身使用。
for athletes to complete their warm-ups.
总体而言，将有超过 40 个比赛场馆分布在洛杉矶全市，
Overall, there'll be more than 40 venues spread across the city
从圣莫尼卡到阿纳海姆，从帕萨迪纳到长滩。
from Santa Monica to Anaheim and from Pasadena to Long Beach.
说到如何抵达这些场馆，你可能会想——
As for getting to these sites,
这是洛杉矶，大家肯定都开车来吧。
you might think that with this being LA,
people are just going to pull up in their cars.
但市长卡伦·巴斯的计划，恰恰相反。
But according to Mayor Karen Bass, the plan is actually
for people to do the exact opposite.
>> 核心目标就是：进场馆，不开车。
>> The main push will be no cars to the venues.
巴斯市长表示，奥运会是推动城市实现变革性变化的难得机遇。
Bass says the Olympics are a chance to make transformative change for the future.
好吧，但考虑到很多人仍然把洛杉矶视为一座以汽车为中心的城市，
Okay, but because many people will still consider LA
这个想法听起来有点异想天开。
to be a very car- centric city, that idea sounds kind of crazy.
也许并非如此——毕竟，自洛杉矶上一次举办奥运会以来，
Or maybe not, because since the last time LA hosted the Olympics,
这座城市已经建立起了一套全新的出行方式：地铁系统。
the cities introduced a completely new way of getting around the metro system.
1990 年，就在那届奥运会结束仅六年后，洛杉矶开通了第一条线路，
In 1990, just 6 years after the event, the city unveiled its first line,
"天使之城"的居民终于有了除驾车之外的另一种出行选择——轨道交通。
finally giving Angelinos the option to travel by rail instead of road.
>> 这真的是一项迫切需要的东西。
>> Something that's really needed.
嗯，可能我这几个月都开不了车，
Well, probably I can't drive my car for three more months,
那我就坐这个吧，挺快的。
so maybe I'll just ride this fast.
>> 我们期盼这一天很久了。
>> We've been looking forward to this a long time.
>> 地铁蓝线开通那天，是一个承诺的兑现——
>> Opening day of the Metro Blue Line was the delivery of a promise
在接下来的二十年里，轨道线路将不断延伸，连接各个社区，
that over the next two decades, rail lines would emerge to link communities
为这片土地带来全新的出行方式。
and bring a new form of mobility to the county.
这个承诺实现了吗？
Was that promise kept?
快进四分之一个世纪，
Well, fast forward a quarter of a century
现在的地铁网络已延伸超过 100 英里，
and the network looks like this,
覆盖全市各地。
with well over a 100 miles of routes now stretching across the city.
其中大量建设工作完成于多年前，
While much of that work took place years ago,
但自 LA 2028 宣布以来，这套基础设施又新增了不少改善。
quite a lot's been done to this piece of infrastructure
since the LA 2028 announcement.
截至 2025 年 6 月，
As of June 2025, the rail system has finally been linked
地铁系统终于通过 K 线和 C 线与机场实现了直接连接。
up to the airport on the K and C lines.
期待已久的自动旅客捷运系统也将于 2026 年跟进开通。
An automated people mover, also long awaited, is set to follow on in 2026.
届时，新的地铁换乘中心
That'll provide a new direct rail link
与洛杉矶国际机场（LAX）各航站楼之间将有全新的直达轨道连接。
between the new Metro Transit Center and the LAX terminals.
另一个近期进展的例子是蓝线南段，如今更名为 A 线，
Another example of recent progress is the southern section of the Blue Line,
从科姆普顿一路向南通往长滩，
now called the A- Line, heading straight out of Compton down to Long Beach,
该线路已于 2019 年完成轨道、电力线路、道岔及控制系统的全面升级。
the route was given upgraded tracks, power lines, switching, and control systems back in 2019.
此外，还有东区交通走廊，
Then there's the East Side Transit Corridor, which is going to link downtown
计划将市中心与洛杉矶县东南部四座所谓的"门户城市"相连。
to four of the so-called gateway cities in Southeast LA County.
第一期工程从小东京延伸至东洛杉矶的大西洋站，
The first phase connecting Little Tokyo to the Atlantic Station in East Los Angeles
作为 E 线的一部分，已于 2023 年建成通车。
as part of the Eline completed back in 2023.
但可以说，目前最重要的扩建工程仍在施工之中。
But arguably the most important upgrade of all is still under construction.
对于奥运会乃至洛杉矶未来最为关键的项目，
The project that is most critical not only for the games
是正在威尔希尔大道地下建造的地铁线路。
but for the future of Los Angeles
is the subway that's being built under Wilshire Boulevard.
>> 他指的是 D 线延伸段。
>> He's referring here to the Dline extension.
这条线将从联合车站出发，
It's going to run from Union Station
穿越城市最繁华的商业零售区，
through one of the city's biggest retail and commercial districts
一路延伸至西区。
all the way out to Westside.
>> 那是一条穿行于高密度走廊的大运量系统，
>> That's a highcapacity system in a very dense corridor
它能运送的人数，远比公交车快，
and it will move a ton of people much faster than buses can um
也远比汽车高效。
and much obviously much more effectively than than cars.
>> 尽管包含七座新站的全线要到 2027 年才能通车，
>> While the full routes with its seven stations isn't due to finish until 2027,
但隧道掘进工程已于 2024 年完工。
the tunneling for it concluded back in 2024.
两台隧道掘进机（盾构机）历时五年，挖通了这条 14 公里长的新线路，
Two tunnel boring machines spent 5 years digging the 14 km new line,
设计日运量约 3 万人次。
which is set to carry around 30,000 people a day.
洛杉矶地铁局称之为市交通局有史以来承担的最复杂工程壮举之一。
One LA Metro called it one of the most complex engineering feats
the city's transit authority has ever undertaken.
工人们每天掘进约 15 米，
As workers excavated around 50 ft of tunnel each day,
途中遭遇了含气地层、油砂层和废弃油井等种种障碍。
they discovered obstacles like gassy ground, tar sands, and abandoned oil wells.
所幸，当这条线路投入运营后，
Thankfully, passengers are going to move through it a lot faster
乘客将能在不到 30 分钟内从市中心直达西洛杉矶。
when it's in operation as they travel from downtown to West LA
in less than 30 minutes.
这些工程都是"28×28"交通计划的组成部分，
These works are all part of what's called the 28x 28 initiative
该计划由洛杉矶前任市长于 2018 年发布。
announced by the city's former mayor in 2018.
没错，就是 28 个交通项目，
It's a list of, yep, 28 transport projects
洛杉矶市计划在奥运会开幕前全部建成。
that the city of Los Angeles planned to complete in time for the games.
总造价预计超过 260 亿美元。
All due to cost more than $26 billion in total.
目前，大约三分之一的项目已经投入运营。
So far, around a third of them are in operation.
当然，推动市民乘坐轨道交通只是目标之一。
Now, getting people to travel by rail isn't the only objective.
"无车"策略并不意味着彻底封路。
A no car strategy doesn't mean no roads at all.
在洛杉矶这样的城市，那根本行不通。
That would be impossible in a place like LA.
坚持开车的人将不得不把车停在场馆以外的区域，
Those who still insist on driving
或者选择乘坐网约车、骑自行车、骑电动滑板车
are going to have to park away from the venues
前往规划中的综合出行枢纽。
or travel by Uber, bike, or scooter
via one of the planned mobility hubs.
对于一个距离硅谷不远的赛事来说，
For an event not far from Silicon Valley,
数字工具成为应对洛杉矶挑战的解决方案之一，
it's no surprise that digital tools
并不令人意外。
are going to be part of the solution to LA's challenges.
事实上，充分利用数据及 AR、VR、AI 等技术，
In fact, making the best use of data
已经成为不可或缺的一环。
and technologies like AR, VR, and AI has become essential.
这些技术正在迅速成为确保
They're quickly becoming the way to ensure
基础设施和大型资本项目按时按预算交付的
that complex infrastructure and capital projects like this
关键手段。
are delivered on time and on budget.
毕竟，研究表明，92% 的项目都未能兑现承诺，
After all, research shows that 92% of projects don't meet their commitments
原因包括前期规划不足、人才短缺、法规频繁变动，以及日益增长的利益相关者审查压力。
due to poor upfront planning, talent shortages, shifting regulations, and increasing stakeholder scrutiny.
因此，相关组织正意识到，
So, the organizations behind them are now finding
必须以不同的方式行事，才能避免陷入那些熟悉的陷阱——
they have to do things differently to avoid falling into familiar traps.
比如过时的流程、各自为政的运营模式，
think outdated processes, siloed operations,
以及足够绕满整座奥运体育场的繁文缛节。
and enough red tape to, I don't know, wrap an entire Olympic stadium.
坦率地说，面对这一切，很难知道该往哪个方向走——
Quite honestly, it can be difficult to know which way to turn,
而这，正是埃森哲出场的时候。
which is where Accenture comes in.
与埃森哲合作，项目团队得以提升
By teaming up with Accenture, project teams are raising their game
从初始概念到项目竣工全周期的交付水平。
with delivery from initial concept all the way through to completion.
埃森哲汇聚了全球逾 5000 名资本项目专家，
Accenture brings together over 5,000 capital project experts worldwide
将经过实战检验的执行力
with a unique blend of fieldproven execution leadership
与战略、建筑技术、项目管控等领域的深厚专业知识融为一体。
and deep expertise across strategy, construction tech, and project controls.
有这样一位全球领军者为你保驾护航，
And with a global leader behind you, your project strategy
你的项目战略不只是挑战常规，而是真正超越常规。
won't just challenge the norm, it'll outperform it.
想了解埃森哲如何帮助你克服最棘手的项目挑战——
To see how Accenture can help you overcome your toughest project challenges
从交付绩效提升，到人才发展与 AI 规模化应用——
from delivery performance to developing talent and scaling AI,
请访问 accenture.com/ICP，或点击简介中的链接。
visit accenture.com/ICP or click the link in the description.
好了，让我们回到洛杉矶，
Now, let's get back to Los Angeles
看看这座城市已经在尝试哪些新技术方案。
and see how the city has already been trying out some new tech ideas.
赛事期间不是测试新技术的理想时机，
The games are not the ideal place to test new technologies,
但眼下正是为奥运会测试新技术的好时机。
but now is a good time to test new technologies for the games.
所以，我们确实应该去做这件事。
And so we should be doing that.
我们有时间去测试一些可能非常有用的想法。
We have time to test some ideas that could be uh very useful.
举个例子，我是按需公交的坚定支持者。
Now for example, I am a big believer in on demand uh transit.
我曾参与在洛杉矶建立地铁微型公交系统，
I I helped set up the metro micro system here in Los Angeles
这是一家按需微型公交运营商。
which is a microransit provider.
我认为，按需微型公交至少能在奥运会的"最后一公里"服务中发挥重要作用，
I think microtransit has a role to play
甚至可以做得更多。
at least in first class mile services
if not more for the Olympic games.
我们已经在测试这项服务了。
And we've already been testing that service.
但替代私家车的主要方案，将是节能公交车——
But the main alternative to private vehicles will be energy efficient buses
官员们希望在赛事开幕前让其投入运营。
that officials hope to have running in time for the games.
计划订购超过 2000 辆，
They plan to order more than 2,000 of them
并开辟专用高速公路车道，
and to bring in dedicated freeway lanes
确保公交不受拥堵影响。
so they're not held up in traffic.
>> 这公交车太棒了，就是棒。
>> The bus is great. It's just great.
什么都运转得很好，真的很酷。
Everything work great and it's cool.
太好了，没有堵车。
It's wonderful. No traffic.
就是太好了。
It's just wonderful.
这多少让人想到 1984 年——
This would be a bit of a throwback to 1984
那时候，公交车对于运送观众、防止交通瘫痪至关重要。
when buses were essential for transporting people and preventing gridlock.
然而，目前并不能保证这些公交车真的会按时到位，
And yet, there's no guarantee at the moment
因为采购资金有赖于联邦拨款，
that these buses are actually going to arrive
而这已经成为一个棘手的问题。
because they're subject to federal funding,
which has become a difficult issue.
洛杉矶交通官员已向特朗普政府申请逾 30 亿美元的联邦资金。
LA transit officials have requested more than $3 billion from the Trump administration.
这笔钱还将用于资助其他交通项目，
That money would also be used to pay for other transport projects
例如为运动员和赛事工作人员建立新的高速公路快速车道系统，
like a new system of fast lanes on the freeways
以加快城市内的通行速度。
to get athletes and event workers around the city quicker.
尽管国会已于 2026 年初批准了一大笔资金，
But while Congress did approve a large chunk of funding in early 2026,
但仍远低于目标数字，
it falls quite a way short of the target figure,
这让外界对于剩余资金能否、以及何时到位
which raises questions about when or if
产生了疑问，
the rest of the money is going to come in,
尤其是当美国总统
especially when the US president's relationship
与洛杉矶市长、加利福尼亚州长之间的关系
with the mayor of LA and the governor of California
一度颇为冷淡的时候。
has been a little bit frosty at times.
如果唐纳德·特朗普某天认为
And so if Donald Trump decides at a given moment
洛杉矶不够配合，
that Los Angeles is misbehaving by his standards,
他完全可能——也很可能——告诉交通部：
um he could and he might well tell the Department of Transportation
不是 32 亿，只给 12 亿，或者随便给个数字。
not 3.2 billion, only 1.2 billion or whatever that number might be.
到那时，洛杉矶该怎么办？
Uh what is Los Angeles going to do in that circumstance?
那他们就只能从"无车奥运"
Well, they're going to have to go
变成"有车奥运"了。
from the no car games to some car games.
这在一定程度上或许解释了，
It could partly explain why organizers now describe the next Olympics
为何主办方现在将下届奥运会定义为"公交优先"而非"无车出行"。
as a transit first games instead of no cars.
这并不意味着他们在全盘倒退。
That's not to say they're making a complete U-turn.
远非如此。
Far from it.
无论发生什么，公共交通都将是人们预期出行的主要方式，
Whatever happens, public transit is going to be the main way
而这是完全可以实现的。
that people are expected to travel
and it can be done.
如果你能做好沟通、讨论和规划，
If you do the right kind of communication and discussion and planning uh
把替代方案真正落实到位，
and you put those alternatives out there,
我认为这完全有可能做到。
I think it is very possible.
举个简单的例子：我最近为好莱坞露天剧场做了一些工作，
Just to give a quick example, I mean, I did some work recently
那是洛杉矶一处非常著名、以汽车出行为主的场所。
for the Hollywood Bowl, uh,
which is a very famous and pretty autocentric, uh, venue here in Los Angeles.
现在，已经有超过 50% 的观众选择乘坐公交车前往好莱坞露天剧场。
We've got over 50% of people now going to the Hollywood Bowl by bus.
这不是什么奇迹。
It wasn't a miracle.
而是有效的规划在起作用——
It was that it was effective planning
让公交真正好用，
and making those buses work really well
让停车费贵到它本该有的价格。
and making parking cost what it should cost, which is a lot.
如果你合理定价停车位和道路使用，
Uh, and if you if you price the parking and the roads effectively
同时提供真正到位的公共交通服务，
and you put the transit service out there,
公交自然会成为最便捷的选择，
it will be the most convenient option
人们就会去用它。
and people will use it.
>> 然而，有几个基础设施项目的完工日期
>> However, several infrastructure schemes have had their completion dates
已经推迟到了奥运会之后。
pushed back to after the games.
东区走廊第二期工程
Phase 2 of the East Side Corridor
最早要到 2035 年才能完工，
isn't due to complete until at least 2035,
而且届时甚至还不是全线通车。
and that won't even be the full line.
这是"28×28"计划中 11 个不得不被剔除的
It's one of 11 projects originally in the 28 by 2028
项目之一。
that have had to be removed.
这些项目被替换为其他进度更快、
They've been substituted for other schemes
或已运营、更有可能在截止日期前完成的方案。
that are either in progress or operational
and are more likely to hit the deadline.
尽管这可能没有听起来那么糟糕——
Although it might not be as bad as it sounds
名单上的许多项目，
because many of the names in that list
从一开始就被认为目标过于激进。
were seen as too ambitious from the start.
我认为，"28×28"计划中的很多项目，
A lot of the projects in 28 by 28 I think
更多是一种愿景——
were much more aspirational of
"要是能完成这些就好了"——
like wouldn't it be great if we got this done
而不是所有项目都真正具有可行性，
but not all of them were realistic
我想当时的决策者心里也清楚这一点。
and I think I think the folks who were there at the time
knew that.
那么，我们有信心说，
So can we be confident that the LA Olympics
洛杉矶奥运会的场馆、配套基础设施和赛事本身
the venues the supporting infrastructure and the event itself
将按时就绪、成就一届成功的奥运会吗？
is going to be done on time creating a successful games?
能在预算内完成，或者至少不严重超支吗？
Will it come in under budget again or at least not way over?
安德鲁认为，尽管存在政治上的尴尬，
Andrew thinks the signs look promising despite the political awkwardness
但凭借票务计划、电视版权合同和赞助商资源，前景还是相当乐观的。
due to its ticket sales program, TV contracts, and sponsorships.
但这绝不会轻松。
But it still won't be easy.
>> 我希望他们能在总体上做到收支平衡。
>> I'm hopeful that they'll be able to come in on balance.
但关于这个"无车计划"，
But all I would say with regard to
我想说的是，它确实
the no plan, the no no cars plan
在奥运目标方面造成了一定风险，
is that it does create some vulnerability
both in terms of the goals of the Olympics
在资金方面也带来了一些隐患。
and some vulnerability in terms of of the financing.
尽管如此，洛杉矶仍有时间
Despite this, there's still time for LA
完成那些关键的收尾项目，
to finish those last few projects that are essential
并克服前行路上的其他障碍。
and overcome any other hurdles it finds in its way.
毕竟，这是美国及其第二大城市再次证明自己的机会——
After all, it's a chance for America and its second city
证明自己有能力承办全球最盛大的舞台。
to prove once again that it can put on the biggest of shows.
>> 我非常希望世界上的其他地方
>> I would love for the rest of the world
能看到洛杉矶有多精彩。
to see how fantastic Los Angeles is.
你知道，人们喜欢拿洛杉矶开玩笑，
You know, people like to make fun of Los Angeles uh
说它是一座依赖汽车、有些浮华的城市。
for being a place that is car dependent and often vapid.
我觉得这些话确实有几分道理，
And I think that those things have a grain of truth to them,
但这座城市有太多值得被世界看见的东西。
but there's so much more to it
that I'd love for the world to see.
这是我们向世界展示的机会。
And this is our opportunity to show that.
本视频由埃森哲赞助播出。
This video was sponsored by Accenture.
点击下方链接，了解更多关于埃森哲的信息。
You can learn more about Accenture at the link below.
别忘了，当你们花时间
Don't forget that when you guys take the time
去关注我们的视频赞助商时，
to go and check out our video sponsors,
对频道的支持意义重大。
it massively helps the channel.
一如既往，如果你喜欢这个视频，
And as always guys, if you enjoyed this video
并希望持续收看这个全球权威建筑工程视频频道的更多内容，
and you want to get more from the definitive video channel for construction,
记得订阅 The B1M。
make sure you subscribe to the B1M.